Finding Aid for the Sami Assaad Aintabi Collection of Arabic Manuscripts LSC.0833
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Rawdat al-'ulama 'wa-nuzhat al-fudalaa, 1275 H.; 77; 172 leaves (numbered). 23 lines.; 19.5 cm. (Box 17)
  Followed by another text (same had) an analysis of rhetorical figures in the Quran and by another text with the heading: Surat ar-Rahman, apparently a commentary on that sura.
  Scribe[?]: 'Abdallah ibn Ibrahim.
  Ref: GAL S I 361 [?].
- (Kitab) Kashf al-asrar 'an lisan at-tair wal-azhar., 78; No pagination. 19 lines.; 19.5 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-ba 'id fi qurbihi al-qarib fi bu' dihi."
- Sharh al-Qasida al-ramiza lil Khazraji, 1130 H.; 79; 1 vol. 21 lines.; 20.5 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit: "qala al-'abd al-faqir ila al-maula al-ghaniy Muhammad Ibn Abi al-Dannamini ..."
  Title on Manuscript: Sharh al-Khazrajiya.
  Scribe: Ibrahim al-Akhtarini.
  Ref: GAL II, 26.
- Hashiya 'ala tafsir al-kashshaf, n.d.; 80; No Pagination. 18 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit[?]: "Qualuchu asluhu 'an ma fa-hudhifa 'l-alif hadhfan kathiran."
  For hashiyas bearing same title, GAL S II, 90, 593, 639.
- Kitab al-mujiz fi 'l qurra' as-sab 'a, n.d.; 83; No pagination. 14 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit[?]: "Rabbi yassir akhbarana al-qadi ... Abu Kansour Sa' id ibn Ahmad ibn Omar al-Jaziri."
  Ref: for author GAL I 407. S I 720.
- Sharh as-Sanusi, n.d.; 84; No pagination. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit[?]: "al-Hamau lillah alladhi shahada bi-wujudihi jami' al-ka init."
- Bulugh al-amani fi 'aqidat ash-Shaibani, 1088 H.; 85; 89 leaves. 18 lines.; 20,5 cm. (Box 17)
  Incipit[?]: "al-Hamdu lillah 'lladhi tarrada bi' l wahdaniya wa' l-qidm."
  Scribe[?]: Ibrahim ibn Mahmud.
  Ref: for author GAL II 292. S II 402.
- ibn Ja'far ibn al-Tarrah (?), 1013 H.; 88/1; No pagination. 21 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ala jazil ata'ihi."
  Scribe: Ata ibn Ma' tuq al-Ulwani.
- [No further description available], 1041 H.; 88/2; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi khassa nabiyana Muhammad ..."
  Scribe: 'Sta'ibn Ma'tue al-'Ulwani no pagination. 21 lines.
- al-Iowa' fi hall alfaz Abi Shuja', 1241 H.; 90; 212 leaves. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 19)
  First 33 leaves are missing.
  With a margin text.
  Scribe: Ahmad ibn ash-shaikh 'Umar khalifat ash-shaikh Mansur.
  Ref: GAL II 320; S II 441 (?).
- Mishat al-Masabih, n.d.; 91; No pagination. Approximately 18 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 19)
  First page(s) and end missing.
  Ref: GAL S II 263.
- al-khulasa fi usul na' rifat al-hadith (khulasat al-mukhtasar), 1118 H.; 92/1; No pagination. 19 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Ref: GAL S II 67.
- [No further description available] [3 titles], 1118 H.; 92; No pagination. Lines vary.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Contents.-
  1. at-Tibi, Abu Abdallah (Muhammad) Sharafaddin al-Hussain ibn Abdullah ibn Muhammad: al-khulasa fi usul ma'rifat al-hadith (khulasat al-mukhtasar).
  2. Mella Ibrahim ien Haidar al-Kurdi al-Husainabadi: Has*hiyat sharh mukhbat-al-fikar.
  3. Sharh sharh nukhabat al-fikar.
- Hashiyat sharh nukhabat-al-fikar, 1118 H.; 92/2; No pagination. 23 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit[?]: "Qauluhu al-hamdu lillahi al-hamdu huwa 'l-wash fli'l-jamil ala 'l-jamil al-ikhtiyari? ala jihat al-tazim."
  Ref: for author GAL S N I 285.
  For sharh nukhabat-al-fikar GAL II, 394, 395, no.10.
- [No further description available], 1118 H.; 92/3; No pagination. Lines vary.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu lillahi 'lladhi sabbaha kalamahu al-qadim."
  Ref: for sharh nukhabat al-fikar GAL II, 395.
- [No further description available], n.d.; 93; 10 leaves (incomplete). 21 lines.; 19.5 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit[?]: "al Hamdu lillah alladhi ikhtara'a kurat al-malakut min ghair mithal mithal sabiq."
  End is missing.
- al-Fatawa al-Rahimiya, 1111-1112 H.; 94; 285 leaves. Approximately 25 lines. (Box 19)
  Incipit[?]: "Hamdan liman fataha abwab al-haqa iq."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad ibn 'Abdarrahim al-Lutfi.
  Ref: GAL II 436 S II 648.
- Awwal juz' min al-juz' ath-thani min sharh al-mukhtasar, n.d.; 95; No pagination. Two handwritings: 15 and 23 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "Bab dhukira fihi ___ was-said wa-ma yata' allaqu bihima."
- Qurrat al- 'ain bi-ada' an-nusukain, 1179 H.; 97; 20 leaves. 19 lines. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi ja 'ala baitahu al- 'atiq mathabat an-nas."
- Sharh as-sirajiyya, 1091 H.; 98/1; No pagination. 22 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al-'alamin hamd al-shakirin."
  Scribe: Mustafa al-Imam.
- Hall al-mushkilat fi l-fara' id, 1213 H.; 98/2; No pagination. 23 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-malik al- alim al- 'allama."
  Ref: GAL II 432.
- Sharh al-Rahbiya, n.d.; 99; No pagination. 21 lines.; 20,5 cm. (Box 19)
  Incipit[?]: "Qala al-Shaikh al-Imamal-'alim al-'allama al-kussab wa'l-fardiyia Sibawaihi zamanihi wa-farid'asrihi wa-awanihi Badraddin Muhammad sibt al-Maridini."
  Ref: for author & work GAL II 357.
- Mafatin ad-darriya fi ibhbat al-qwanin ad-dawiya, 1175 H.; 100; 16 leaves. 19 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "Subhan alladhi akhless l-insan bin-nuta min alam al-jamad."
  Manual of Persian grammer in Arabic.
  Scribe: Muhammad Se id ibn Muhammad al-imam.
- Risalat khulasat ma tahassale alaihi as-sa un fi adwiyat daf al-waba wat-ta un, n.d.; 101; No pagination. 11 lines.; 15.5 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "Sudhanaka Allehumma wa bi-hamdika ya murih al-qulub."
  Ref: For author, GAL II 274, 333, S II 385.
- Sharh risalat al-Qushairi, 1113 H.; 105; No pagination. Approximately 30 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit[?]: "qala sayyiduna wa-mawlana shaikh mashayikh al-isla ... Abu Yahya Zakariya al-Ansa4i."
  Ref: for author GAL II 99.
- [No further description available], 921 H.; 106; No pagination. 13 lines.; 14 cm. (Box 16)
- [No further description available], 1158 H.; 107; 97 leaves. 17 lines.; 15.5 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah 'ala jazil ni 'matihi."
- Masabih al-Ukhrawi mukhtasar diya' al-ma nawi, n.d.; 108; 260 leaves. 23 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu lillahi rabb al- alamin wa'l 'aquiha lil-mut-taqin."
  Manuscript incomplete.
  Ref: for author GAL S II, 1043.
  For diya' al-ma 'mawi GAL S I 649.
- Shubbak (al-munasakhat bil-jawal fi 'ilm al-fara 'id, n.d.; 109; 15 leaves. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "I 'lam anna a'mal al-munasakhat bil-jadwal ..."
  Ref: GALS II 155.
- ar-Risala ash-shasiyya fi ilm al-mantiq, 1080 H.; 110; 27 leaves. 17 lines.; 17 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi abda'a nizam al-Wujud."
  Ref: GAL I 466 S I 845 (?).
  Here the title reads ar-Risala ash-shamsiyya fi'l-qawa'id al-mantiqiyya.
- al-mukhatasar fi mustalah ahl al-athar, 1305 H.; 111; 6 leaves. 14 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al-'alamin wa-ashhadu anna la ilaha illa'llah."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad As ad ibn Muhammad Naji_____ al- Aintabi.
  Ref: GAL II 321.
- Risala fi' l-mantiq, 1113 H.; 112; 8 leaves. 23 lines.; 17 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "Hadhihi risala fi 'ilm al-mantiq."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad Hasabullah al-Hasabi.
  Ref: GAL S II 472.
- Sharh gharami sahih, 1262 H.; 113; 6 leaves. 20 lines.; 22.5 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "Qala sh-Sheikh al-Imam al- allama 'Izz ad-Din Abu Abdallah Muhammad ibn Jama 'a."
  Scribe[?]: Abd al-Ghafur al-Sabbagh.
  Ref: for author GAL II 72 S II 78.
- Kitab al-arba'in (fi mabani al-Islam wa-qawa'id al-ahkam), 1212 H.; 114; 6.1. 24 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al-'alamin as-samawat wal-ard."
  Scribe: Muhammad ibn' Ali Sa'd al- Haddad.
  Ref: GAL S I 682.
- Kitab al-arba'in (fi mabani al-Islam wa-qawa'id al-ahkam), 1212 H.; 114; 6.1. 24 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
- [No further description available], 1156 H.; 116; 42 leaves. 20 or 28 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-malik al-karim."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad Ramadan al-Gharazi.
- Husul ar-rifq bi-usul ar-rizq, 1306 H.; 117; 10pp. 19 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah wa-kafa wa-salam 'ala ibadihi lladhina stafa."
  Scribe[?]: Isa ibn Hasan ibn Bakri al-Bayanuni.
  Ref: GAL II 149 SII 186, 86.
- [No further description available], 1190 H.; 118; 19 leaves. 19-21 lines.; 19 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah mujid al-'ilm lil-mujiddin."
- Nazm al-badi fi madh ash-shafi', 1213 H.; 119; 16 leaves. 23 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Ref: GAL II 158 SII 198,313
- Jawara fi' r-ras' (qad nuzimat fa' idatan fi' l-wad, 1324 H.; 120; 32pp. 17 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah wa-kafa was salat 'ala 'n-nabi al-mustafa."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad Jamil (ibn Yusuf Diya').
- Sharh al- Adudiyya li-Abf 'l-Qasim 'Ali al-Samarqandi (?), 1161 H.; 121; 36 leaves. 27 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah 'llladhi kammala bi sharaf al-wad' sha'n al-a'lam."
- al-nafhat al-mi' tara fi bayan al-haqiqa wal-majaz wal-isti' ara, 1200 H.; 122; 12 leaves. 23 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi fataha muqfalat al-fuhum."
- al-risala al-waqi'a ala r-risala l-'Adudiyya (sharh ar-risala l-Adudiyya?), 1179 H.; 123/1; 14 leaves. 17 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi a\khassa' l-insan bi-ma'rifat awda al-kalam."
  Scribe[?]: Yusuf ibn al-Sheikh Abdallah.
  Ref: for author, GAL SII 259.
- Hashiya ala Shrh al-risala l- Adudiyya, 1179 H.; 123/2; 8 leaves. 17 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 16)
  Incipit: "qawluhu khassa l-insan bi-ma 'rifat awda al-kalam.. ."
- [No further description available], 1187 H.; 124/1; 16 leaves. 21 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi allama bi l-qalam, 'allama l-insan ma lam ya'lam."
- Tuhfat al-a' yan bil-kalam 'ala lafzatay amintum wal-am, n.d.; 124/2; 6pp. 21 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "hadhihi tuhfat ...."
- Ujalat dhawi 'l-intibaah fi tahqiq la ilah illallah, 1070 H.; 129; 5 leaves. 23 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-ghani al-hamid."
  Scribe[?]: Author's Manuscript.
  Ref: GAL SII 521.
- Durrat al-tawhid, n.d.; 125; 27 leaves. 13 lines.; 16.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "yaqulu Ahmad al-Damanhuri."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad Salah ad-Din.
  Ref: GAL SII 498.
- Sharh qasidat Jamal ad-Din (Muhammad ibn Abdallah) fi abniyat al-af 'al, 1265 H.; 126; 20 leaves. 21 lines.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "qala 'sh-sheikh al-imam Badr-ad-Din ibn ash-sheikh Jamal ad-Din ..."
- Ifadat al-wa i bi-ahkam al-muttarid wash-shadhdh was-sama 'i, 1214 H.; 127/1; 41 leaves. 32 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ... waba 'du fa- innahu wasala-s-su' al."
- Hashiya ala' l-kafi li-Muhammad ad-Damanhuri, 1260 H.; 127/2; 3 leaves. 21 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
- al- 'Izzi, 823 H.; 128; 10 leaves. 15 lines.; 17 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ... i 'lam anna' t-tasrif fi l-luqha at-taghyir."
  Scribe[?]: Khidr ibn Ahmad Rajab.
  Ref: GAL SI 497.
- Sharh al-Ajurrmiya, 998 H.; 130; 22 leaves. 17 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "qala l-imam al- allama ... khalid ibn Abdallah al-Azhari ash-Shafi'i."
- Durar al-kunuz, 1061 H.; 131; 19 leaves. 19 lines.; 18.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "li-hamd ilah 'al-alamin" (?).
- al-abhath al-mukhallasa fi hukm kaiy al-himmasa (ala madhhab al-imam al-a zam Abi Hanifa), 1098 H.; 132/1; 3 leaves. 18 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-muyassir lil-umur."
  Ref. GAL SII 473,34
- Risala fis-sibgh bin-najas, 1098 H.; 132/2; 4 leaves. 20 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah wahdihi."
- al-falah; mukhtasar talkhis al-muftah, 847 H.; 133; 24 leaves. 13 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi an 'ama ala l-insan."
  Ref: for author GAL Sl 620[?].
- al-musayara fi 'l- 'aqa id al-munjiya fi 'l-akhire, n.d.; 134; 8 leaves. 23 lines. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu liman rasama 'ala safahat al-ka 'inat dala' il tawhidihi."
  Ref: GAL II 82.
- Risalat rad' al-nahs 'an al-akhdh 'ala al-ahkam al maks, 1306 H.; 135; 2.5pp. 18 lines.; 23.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Hamdan liman aw 'ada man ghaiyyara maalim shari atihi bi-wakhim 'adhabihi."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad As 'ad ibn Muhammad Naji ____ al-Aintabi.
- Ghunyat al-mubtadi' fi bayan shru t al-imam al-muqtadi ('ala madhhab al-Imam al-Shafi l), n.d.; 136; 16 leaves. 19 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ... was-salat was-salam 'ala sayyid al-mursalin wa-imam al-muttaqin."
- Fath al-Jawwad., 137; 19 leaves. 26 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi ba'atha Muhammad ... rahmatan lil- alamin."
  Ref: GAL S II 440.
- Mimiyya, 1126 H.; 138; 29 leaves. 25 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Qala l-faqir ila mawlahu dhi 'l-karam Ulwan (?) dhu 'dh-dhanb wal- 'isyan."
  Scribe[?]: Hashim ibn al-Hajj Ikhlas.
- Sharh al-waraqat, n.d.; 138; 18 leaves. 29 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ... was salat was-salam ala sayyid al-mursalin habib Allah Abi 'l-Qasim Ahmad Khatim an-nabiyyin."
  Ref: GAL S II 85.
- Hikmat al-furud wal-hawd fi dhalika, 967 H.; 139; 22 leaves. 19 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al-hayy alladhi la sabil lil-mawt 'alaihi."
- ala qa' idat as-sada ash-Shafi' iyya, n.d.; 140; 9 leaves. 17 lines.; 17.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi waffaqa litahsil a;-'ilm man sha'a."
- Manasik al-hajj, n.d.; 141; 19 leaves. 15 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi amara khalilahu bi an yu 'adhdhina fi 'n-nas bil-hajj."
  Ref: for author, GAL S II 902.
- Risala fi taqsim al-murabba 'lladhi fi matn al-sirajiyya fi l-fara 'id, 1171 H.; 142; 6 leaves. 21 lines.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi qaddara 'l-fara 'id fi kitabihi."
  Scribe[?]: al-Hajj Ahmad al-Bakrawi (?).
- Sharh kitab al-shubbak (by ibn al-Ha'im, Shahab ad-Din Ahmad), 1152 H.; 143; No pagination. 20 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Yaqulu 'l abd al-faqir ila rahmat rabbihi al-ghanily Muhammad ibn 'Abd al-Quddus."
- Risalat' ujalat al-rakib li-taqrib al-mubtadi fi muraja'at al-qamus, n.d.; 144; 8 leaves. ca. 25 lines.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "hadhihi 'r-risala al-mawsuma bi ujalat ar-rakib ..."
- Kifayat al-ghulam, 1308 H.; 145; 8 leaves. 13 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ala ma wafaqa thumma al-salat was salam mutlaqa."
  Scribe[?]: Muhammad As ad ibn Muhammad Naji _____ al- Aintabi.
  Ref: GAL SII 474, 35.
- al-Durr al-wahhaj fima yata 'allequ bil-isra wal-mi 'raj, 1133 H.; 146; 20 leaves. 22 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al-'alamin wa-afdal as-salat wa-ashraf at-taslim 'ala sayyidins Muhammad khatim an-nabiyyin."
  Scribe: Sa 'd ibn al-Hasjj 'Abd al-Wahhaab al-Shafi 'i.
  Ref: for author, GAL II 364.
- Bushra 'l-ka'ib fi liqa al-habib, n.d.; 147; 18 leaves. 23 lines.; 21.5cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah wa-kafa wa-salam 'ala 'ibadihi 'iladhina 'stafa."
  Scribe[?]: Akhasafir ibn al-Sayyid Jamil.
  Ref: GAL II 146 SII 183, 30a.
- [No further description available], n.d.; 148; 6 leaves. 14 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah jami an-nas li-yaumin la raiba fini ... amma ba d, fa-hadhihi asami majami .... ibn Hajar al-Asqalani ..."
  A descriptive list of works by Ibn Hajar al-'Asqalani.
- Diwan, n.d.; 149; 46pp. ca. 21 lines.; 19 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "hadha ad-diwan ila janab Mustafa Jalabi al-Babi waqad imtadaha biha (sic) hadrat 'Abd al-Qadir hina tawallahu."
- Kitab al-fara id, 959 H.; 150; 14 leaves. 17 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah al- 'alim al-hakim."
  Scribe[?]: Arabi ibn Muhammad ibn Qaba.
- silk an-nudar sharh ad-durr al-mukhtar, 117-1173 H.; 151-152; vol.1: 1999 fol.; vol.2: 300 fol. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "al-hamdu lilladi' lladhi ja ala ala ad-din fawqa kui aliyin wa-halla bi-durr al-fiqn al-mukhtar ajyad ai-chatarifa an-nubala..."
  For ad-durr al-mukhtar see GAL; 3.
- Haqa'iq an-nahw al-kubra, 1222 H.; 153; 20 leaves. 22 lines.; 22.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah ... amma ba'd fa-yaqulu 'l-abd al-faqir ila rahmat al-mawla al-qadir."
- (kitab) al-Fara id as-saniha fi nazm an-nuway fi l-fiqh, 1321 H.; 155; 152 leaves. 17 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah te'ala jidduhu subhanahu fa-laysa yuhsa hamduhu."
  A handbook of Hanafi figh written in rhyming couplets and divided into 176 chapters.
- Hashiyat maraqi l-falah lis-saiyid at-Tahtawi., 156; 490 leaves. 23 lines. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi' ayyade' sh-shari 'a bi-wurrathiha wa ...."
  Scribe: Muhammad ibn 'Umar al-Waquif.
  Ref: for maraqi see GAL II 313; S II 430.
- Risala fi ilm at-tasawwuf, 1286 H., 157; 14 leaves. 23 lines.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al- alamin was-salat was-salam ala sayyidina Muhammad ..."
  Scribe[?]: Abdallah ibn Ahmad al-Misri.
- iqaz al-qawabil bit-taqarrub bin-nawafil, 1079 H.; 158; 6 leaves. 27 lines.; 19 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah rabb al- 'alamin."
  Scribe: Musa ibn Ibrahim al-Misri.
  Ref: GAL II 386, S II 520.
- Sharh al-jami as-sahih, n.d.; 158; No pagination. 37 lines.; 32 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-kalam 'ala 'l-basmala mashhur wa-fi-sh shuruh mabsut mastur."
  Manuscript is incomplete at the end.
- Sahih (vol.5), 1138 H.; 160; No pagination. 15 lines.; 26.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Bab du 'a' an-nabiy ... an-nasa ila 'l-Islam wan-nubuwwa."
  Scribe: Yusuf ibn al-shaikh Ibrahim al-Khatib.
- Qasa'id majmu'a fi madh khair al-khalq wa-qisas wa-riwayat fi ghairiha, n.d.; 161; No pagination. Number of lines varies. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Hadhihi al-qasida ..."
- al-Tawdih fi 'l-fiqh al-Hanafi, 1066 H.; 162; No pagination. 25 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Ya sa'ili 'an sifat al-mu' adhdhin."
  Scribe: al-(Hajj) Husain al-mu'arrif.
  Ref: For author, GAL II 224.
- sl-Fawa id al-jalila fi musalsala5 Muhammad ibn Ahmad 'Aqila, n.d.; 163; 29 leaves. 15 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Qala shaikhuna wa-ustadhuna allamatu z-zaman."
  Scribe: Khalil al- Utwi al-'Anjarani.
  Ref: GAL SN II 522.
- Hashiya 'ala shrh as-Sanusiya, 1214 H.; 164; No pagination. 27 lines.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu li-wajib al-wujud."
  Scribe: Ahmad Kashar.
  Ref: GAL II 485.
  Here: Hashiya 'ala sharh as-Sanusiva as-Sughra.
- Risala fi l-fatwa, 1211 H.; 164/9; 23 leaves. (106-128). 15 lines.; 22 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi ja 'ala al-fatwa libas at-taqwa."
- Hishiya 'ali sharh al-Ajurrumiyya, 1107 H.; 165; No pagination. 17 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Hamdan li-man manaha an-nahina nahwa babihi ..."
  Ref: GAL S II 397.
- [No further description available], n.d.; 166; No pagination. 23 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  The beginning and the end are missing.
  A collection of traditions and quotations from Muslim scholars.
- Diwan (?). (?)., 1218 H.; 167; No pagination. No. of lines varies.; 23 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "wa-li-sayyidi Ishaq ibn Yusuf hadhihi al-maqtu 'a."
  In the volume are inserted three facicles belonging apparently to another work and containing short biographies and quotations from the poetry of Ash Sharif ar-Radiy and his.
  Ref: for author, GAL S II 545, 968.
- Sirr ar-ruh, 853 H. (?).; 169; No pagination. 17 lines.; 17 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Qala Allah 'azza wa-jalla wa-yas' alunaka 'an ar-ruh."
- Talkhis fi l-ma' ani, 1015 H.; 171; No pagination. 13 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi ba atha li-salah 'ibadihi fi-al-nash' atein nadhiran.. ."
  Sic in title page.
  In the first page, however: "wa-sammahu... mukhtaran." Hence, the work is apparently: al-mukhtar fi l-ma ani wal-bayan (GAL S II 322).
  Scribe: Muhammad al-Sahr(?).
  Ref: For author, GAL II 231, S II 322.
- [No further description available], n.d.; 172/1; No pagination. 9 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah hamd ash-shakirin was-salat khair al-bariya Muhammad wa-ali at-taiyibin at-tahirin."
- [No further description available], n.d.; 172/2; No pagination. 16 lines.; 18 cm. (Box 9)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi abraza bi'l-fara 'id bi-hujjat riad ash-shar'."
  A work dealing with the laws of inheritance.
- Fusus al-Hikam, n.d.; 173; No pagination. 19 lines.; 19.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu lillah' mumzil al-hikam."
  Ref: GAL I, 442, S I 792, 12.
- Hall al-rumuz wa-mafatih al-kumuz, n.d.; 174; No pagination. 20 lines.; 19.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu lillahi 'lladhi fataha bi-mafatih al-ghu-yub aqful al-qulub."
  Ref: GAL I 451; GAL S I 809.
- Hadi al-qulub ila liqa' al-mahbub, 1107 H.; 175/1; No pagination. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "Qala shaikhuna shaikh al-Islam Abd al-Latif ibn Abd al-Rahman ibn Ghanim al-Maqdisi."
  Scribe: Darwish Mustafa Khatib.
  Ref: GAL II 231.
  Here Hawi al-qulub.
- [No further description available], 1110 H.; 175/2; No pagination. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alim al-ghaib wash-shahada."
- (Kitab) 'aja 'ib al-malakut, 1165 H.; 177; 112 leaves. 13 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "al-Hamdu lillah alladhi kana qable takwin al-ak-wan."
  Scribe[?]: Ahmad ibn shaikh Ibrahim.
  Ref: GAL I 350.
- Tuhfat wahib al-mawahib fi bayan al-maqamat wal-maratib, 1106 H.; 175/3; No pagination. 21 lines.; 21 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: "al-hamdu lillah alladhi salaka bi-awlia' ihi subul ar-rashad."
  Ref: GAL II 231 S II 323.
- Sharh qasidat al-Shahrazuri[?], n.d.; 178/1; 28 leaves. 27 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "al-Hamdu lillah ... wa-qad sa' alani ba d ashabi an a-takallama ala na hadhiki al-qasida."
  Ref: for author GASL II 345.
  For Shahrazuri GAL I 433.
- Kitab al-adab al-adab as-samiya wal-af'al al-sharifa al-mardiya al-qudsiya li-man yuridu tariq as-sadat al-khalavatiya, n.d.; 178/2; Incomplete pagination. 23 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "Hamdan li-man ja'ala adb-dhikr afdal al- 'ibadat wa-ja'ala dhakirahu min afdal al-bariyat wal-makhluqat."
  Ref: GAL SN II 479: al-Adab as-samiya al-Hifniya wal-afal al-sharifa al- aliya li-murid suluk at-tariqa al-Khalwatiya.
  In index: al-adab as-saniya al-Hifniya...
- al-Isfar an asl istikharat a 'mal al-lail wan-nahar, n.d.; 178/3; 19 leaves. 25 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit: partly covered by apiece of paper glued to the corner of the page. In the middle: "amma ba d fa-hadha ayyuha at-talib ar-raghib na yata 'allaq bi l-istikhara li l-arufa allati tu malu li-amr mu'ayyan idha hamma ..."
  Colophon partly missing.
- Risala fi tariqat as-sada an-naqshabandiya, 1170 H.; 178/4; 10 leaves. 23 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu lillah rabb al- alamin was-salat was salan 'ala sayyidina Muhammad."
  Scribe[?]: Abdarrahman al-'Imadi.
- as-Safwa fi bayin tariq akl al-khalwa, n.d.; 178/5; 9 leaves. 19 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Author's manuscript[?].
  Ref: for author GAL S II 457.
- Akhdar ibn Jamil al-Mufarragi, n.d.; 178/6; 25 leaves. 23 lines.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
- Nafa is ad-durar fi tarjamat shaikh al-Islam Ibn Haja, 1181 H.; 178/7; 6 leaves. 31 lines in the pages by the 1st scribe, 26 in the pages by the 2d scribe.; 21.5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "yarulu al-'abd al-faqir ila fadl Allah ta 'ala wa-kara-mihi Abu Bakr ibn Muhammad ibn 'Abdallah Ba 'amr."
  Scribe[?]: ash-shaikh Muhammad and ash-shaikh Mustafa Salih inn Sultan.
  Ref: for author GAL SN II 527.
- al-Misra'i al-i'tiqad Wal-ahadith ad-dalla'alal-qutb wa l-abdal wa'l-awtad, n.d.; 178/8; 13 leaves. followed by 3 more in a different handwritting.; 21.5cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit 1: "abyat latifa min qasida min kalam 'Ali ibn Shirin."
  Incipit 2: "warada l-hadith an an-mabi Muhammad al-Hashini ..."
  A chapter from a risala bearing the title al-Kawakib al-Mudia.
- ash-Shajara al-mufarri' a fi'l masa 'il al-mutanaw- wi 'a, 1134 H.; 179; No pagination. 23 lines.; 20, 5 cm. (Box 18)
  Incipit[?]: "aala mu' allifuhu al-faqir ila 'llah ta 'ala."
  Ref: GAL S II 463.
- al-Hizb al-a'zam, 1088 H.; 180; No pagination. 14 lines.; 20 cm. (Box 9)
  Incipit[?]: "Al-hamdu l'llah rabb al-alamin was-salam ala sayyidina Muhammad."
  Ref: GAL S II 540, no.51.